Debunking /diːˈbʌŋk 揭穿/ the myths of OCD
There's a common misconception /ˌmɪskənˈsɛpʃən 错觉/
that if you like to meticulously  /məˈtɪkjʊləslɪ 异常细致地/
organize your things,
keep your hands clean,
or plan out your weekend
to the last detail,
you might have OCD.
In fact, OCD, which stands
for obsessive /əbˈsɛsɪv 强迫症患者 强迫性的/ compulsive /kəmˈpʌlsɪv 极有趣的，令人着迷的；强迫性的 / disorder,
is a serious psychiatric /ˌsaɪkɪˈætrɪk 精神疾病的/ condition
that is frequently
misunderstood by society
and mental health professionals alike.
So let's start by debunking /diːˈbʌŋk 揭穿/ some myths.
Myth one: repetitive /repetitive 重复的，啰嗦的/ or ritualistic /ˌrɪtjʊəˈlɪstɪk 仪式的/
behaviors are synonymous /sɪˈnɒnɪməs 同义的/ with OCD.
As its name suggests,
obsessive /əbˈsɛsɪv 强迫症患者 强迫性的/ compulsive /kəmˈpʌlsɪv 极有趣的，令人着迷的；强迫性的 / disorder
has two aspects /ˈæspɛkt 特征/:
the intrusive /ɪnˈtruːsɪv 侵入的/ thoughts, images,
or impulses /ˈɪmpʌls  冲动/, known as obsessions /əbˈsɛʃən 强迫症/,
and the behavioral  /bɪˈheɪvjərəl/
compulsions /kəmˈpʌlʃən/ people engage in
to relieve /rɪˈliːv 缓解/ the anxiety /æŋˈzaɪɪtɪ/
the obsessions cause.
The kinds of actions that people often
associate with OCD,
like excessive /ɪkˈsɛsɪv 过多的/ hand washing,
or checking things repeatedly,
may be examples of obsessive /əbˈsɛsɪv/
or compulsive tendencies /ˈtɛndənsɪ 趋势/
that many of us exhibit from time to time.
But the actual disorder is far more rare
and can be quite debilitating /dɪˈbɪlɪˌteɪt 使虚弱/.
People affected have little or no
control over their obsessive thoughts
and compulsive behaviors,
which tend to be time consuming
and interfere with work,
school or social life
to the point of causing
significant /sɪɡˈnɪfɪkənt/ distress /dɪˈstrɛs 忧虑/.
This set of diagnostic /daɪəɡˈnɒstɪk 诊断的/ criteria /kraɪˈtɪərɪə OR kraɪˈtɪərɪən 标准/ is what
separates people suffering from OCD
from those who may
just be a bit more meticulous /məˈtɪkjʊləs 讲究细节的/
or hygiene /ˈhaɪdʒiːn 卫生/ obsessed than usual.
Myth two: the main symptom of OCD
is excessive hand washing.
Although hand washing is the most common
image of OCD in popular culture,
obsessions and compulsions
can take many different forms.
Obsessions can manifest /ˈmænɪˌfɛst 出现；显示 货单；旅客名单/
as fears of contamination /kənˌtæmɪˈneɪʃən 弄脏，污染；污染物/ and illness,
worries about harming others,
or preoccupations /prɪˌɒkjʊˈpeɪʃən 偏见，成见；专心；专心的事物  (尤指精神上)先入为主/ with numbers,
patterns, morality /moʊˈrælɪti 道德/, or sexual /ˈsɛkʃuəl/ identity.
And compulsions can range from
excessive cleaning or double checking,
to the fastidious /fæˈstɪdɪəs 难取悦的，挑剔的，苛求的，有洁癖的/ arrangement of objects,
or walking in predetermined /ˌpriːdɪˈtɜːmɪn 预先决定做/ patterns.
Myth three:
individuals with OCD don't understand
that they are acting irrationally /ɪˈræʃənəlɪ 不合理地/.
Many individuals with OCD actually
understand the relationship
between their obsessions
and compulsions quite well.
Being unable to avoid
these thoughts and actions
despite being aware of their irrationality /ɪˌræʃəˈnælɪtɪ 不合理/
is part of the reason
why OCD is so distressing.
OCD sufferers report feeling crazy
for experiencing anxiety
based on irrational thoughts
and finding it difficult
to control their responses.
So what exactly causes OCD?
The frustrating /frʌˈstreɪt 挫败/ answer
is we don't really know.
However, we have some important clues.
OCD is considered
a neurobiological /ˌnjʊərəʊˌbaɪəˈlɒdʒɪkəl 神经生物学的/ disorder.
In other words, research suggests
that OCD sufferers brains
are actually hardwired  /ˌhɑːdˈwaɪəd  硬连线/
to behave /bɪˈheɪv 行事；表现/ in a certain fashion.
Research has implicated /ˈɪmplɪˌkeɪt 表明…有牵连  暗指/
three regions of the brain
variously involved in social behavior
and complex cognitive /ˈkɒɡnɪtɪv 认识的/ planning,
voluntary /ˈvɒləntrɪ 即兴演奏；自愿者 自愿的/ movement,
and emotional and motivational responses.
The other piece of the puzzle
is that OCD is associated
with low levels of serotonin /ˌsɛrəˈtəʊnɪn 血清素/,
a neurotransmitter /ˌnjʊərəʊtrænzˈmɪtə 神经传递介质/
that communicates between brain structures
and helps regulate vital /ˈvaɪtəl 必不可少的；生命的/ processes,
such as mood, aggression, impulse control,
sleep, appetite /ˈæpɪˌtaɪt 食欲/,
body temperature and pain.
But are serotonin /ˌsɛrəˈtəʊnɪn 血清素/ and activity
in these brain regions the sources of OCD
or symptoms of an unknown
underlying cause of the disorder.
We probably won't know until
we have a much more intimate /ˈɪntɪmɪt 熟悉的；亲密的/
understanding of the brain.
The good news is there are
effective treatments for OCD,
including medications, which increase
serotonin /ˌsɛrəˈtəʊnɪn 血清素/ in the brain
by limiting its reabsorption /ri:əbˈsɔ:pʃən 再吸收/
by brain cells,
behavioral therapy that gradually
desensitizes /ˌdiːˈsensɪˌtaɪz 减少感光性,使不敏感/ patients to their anxieties,
and in some cases,
electroconvulsive /ilektrəukənˈvʌlsiv 电痉挛 / therapy,
or surgery /ˈsɜːdʒərɪ/, when OCD doesn't respond
to other forms of treatment.
Knowing that your own brain
is lying to you
while not being able
to resist its commands can be agonizing /ˈæɡəˌnaɪzɪŋ 极度痛苦/.
But with knowledge and understanding
comes the power to seek help,
and future research into the brain
may finally provide
the answers we're looking for.